so the first couple weeks of this course
这门课程的前几周
are going to be spent on image processing
将讨论图像处理的话题
So for this very first lecture
所以第一节课
all I wanted to do is go through the basics of
我想要做的就是通过Julia语言
how you work with images in the language Julia
介绍一些处理图像的基础知识
now the slides that I'm going through here aren't actual normal slides
现在屏幕上显示的并不是普通的PPT
we're working in what's known as a Pluto notebook
而是叫做Pluto的一种笔记本（注：第一节课提到过）
So at any given point
所以在Pluto中，
you can type code and then output of that code is displayed in some way
你可以任意输入Julia代码，然后它会立刻显示该代码的输出
this makes it really nice to work with images
用这种方法处理图像将会十分方便
And in principle, with these lectures
事实上，在听课过程中
you can follow along if you want
如果你愿意，你可以跟着我们一起敲代码
and basically go through the same code and maybe
事实上只要敲一样的代码，或者
change the inputs or tweak it if you want to explore anything
简单修改一些输入或者参数，就亲身体验代码效果
There are some fun things that we can do with Pluto notebooks
我们可以使用Pluto笔记本做一些有趣的事情
like embed a little webcam applet in here I guess
像在这里嵌入一个小摄像头
And so I can take my picture
这样我就可以拍摄图片
and we can use the output of that picture as a variable
然后可以将该图片的输出用作程序变量
so in this cell  for example
比如，在这个代码块里面
I am defining the variable grant to be something which
我们声明变量grant，并把他作为
basically takes in the data that the webcam recorded
摄像头抓拍获取的照片
and it's going to treat it as a variable
并将其视为程序的变量
And one thing that you will do in this first week's problem set is
在第一周的作业里，你要完成的一个任务
write a function that lets you actually detect thee dges in an image which is pretty cool
就是编写一个函数，来检测图像中的边缘，很酷吧~
so you can put in your own image
所以你可以放自己喜欢的照片
And it's going to find where in that image all of the edges are
程序将在该图片中检测出边缘的分布
very useful in a lot of scientific applications
这在许多科学应用中都非常有用
but before any of that
但在那之前
let's back up to the basics in thinking about what exactly an image is
让我们复习一下，图像到底是什么？
whenever we work with images in computers
在计算机中处理图像时
and I'm guessing a lot of you are well familiar with this
我猜你们当中很多人对此很熟悉
It's essentially a grid of pixels
它本质上是很多格点，每个格点叫做一个像素
So if I pull up some kind of image like a picture of my cat wearing a bow tie
因此，让我们来一张我们家猫带着领结的照片
because why not
……别问我问什么是我们家猫 :)
if you were to take this image
如果我们仔细观察这张照片
and you were to zoom in
并且放大了看
maybe we zoom in onto this sallow eye of Sauron
比如可以放大到这双黄褐色，仔细观察
nice, and you see that eventually you just get little squares
很好，你会发现图上面看到的都是一个个小方块
and each square is a single color
每个方块都是单色
So somewhere in the computer
所以在计算机表示中，
it's representing each of these squares as some data type
它将每个小方块表示为用于一个特定的数据类型
to represent a color
一次来表示一种颜色
and then it's creating a big grid of them
然后构建一个巨大的颜色网格
ou often think of indexing into this array from the upper left corner by the way
顺便说一句，我们习惯上会从图片的左上角开始对这些像素进行编号
So for example
所以举个例子
a first index might tell you how far down to walk
第一个下标告诉我们要往下数多少格
in a second index would tell you how far in to go to get to a certain point
在第二个索引告诉我们要往下数几个格点
so to start doing this with Julia
所以让我们开始用Julia来处理图片吧
let's just get our hands on a specific image
我们会在过程中处理一些真实的图片
here we can see some of the boilerplate for you
在这里有一个图片网站
if you want to pull an image from the web
我们可以从网站上下载图像
So I'm defining a variable 'url'
所以我定义了一个变量'url'
which is simply a string
这是一个字符串
like in any other language
和其他编程语言一样
We use double quotation marks to denote the string
我们使用双引号来表示字符串
and it's going to pull a specific image
它将提取特定的图像
It's going to be Philip, the corgi
这将是Philip，一只小柯基犬
and this next line downloads whatever sitting in that url
下一行代码里会下载这个url中的任何内容
and it's going to save it locally on my machine
并保存到本地
as philip.jpg
命名为philip.jpg
and then in this next cell
然后在下一个代码块中
I'm going to start using the Images library
我将开始使用图像库Images
So this syntax for bringing in a lot of functionality from some other libraries is using here
在Julia中，导入某个库，并且使用库里的函数，用的是using
and then I might define a variable called philip to be 'load...'
然后我可以声明philip的变量，让它等于load(...)
and then the name of this file that now in my system
括号里面是该文件的路径，这个文件已经被保存在系统本地
but whenever we have multiple lines going on like this in a Pluto notebook
注意：如果在Pluto中的一个代码块有多行的内容
I'm going to go ahead and wrap it around
我们需要用begin-end把它包裹起来，作为一整个代码块
and now, when I run this
现在，当我运行这条语句
it's going to display whatever it finds from this last line
它会显示代码块最后一行语句中的返回结果
which in this case is going to be something that's an image Philip
在这种情况下，它将显示Philip这张图片本身
so that's kind of nice
看起来很棒！
that the notebook knows that if I just have an object like Philip that
Pluto笔记本可以猜到，像Philip这样的对象
rather than displaying, you know, the raw underlying data of it
很可能是一张图片，所以它并不显示它的原始数据
that probably what I want is to see the image itself
而是会显示这张图片本身
but maybe we actually want to know a little bit more
但实际上我们可能想更深入了解这张图片
about the raw underlying data for something like this
了解原始数据中的一些特性
So I could type something like typeof(philip)
所以我可以输入"typeof(philip)"
and this is going to give me a type
结果返回了一个变量类型
so this is a little bit confusing
乍一看可能比较令人头疼
but essentially it's telling us that this variable is something that has type `Array'
但是其实它是在告诉我们这个变量是一个数组
and this 2 is telling us it's a two dimensional array
这里的2代表这是个二维数组
so one dimensional array would just be a list of values
因此，一维数组将只是一列数据
and two dimensional arrays is a grid of values
而二维数组则是“一个网格”的数据
and then the type for each one of those values is this RGBX thing
然后每个值的类型是这边的RGBX
So RGB stands for red, green, blue
RGB代表红色，绿色，蓝色
This is a very standard way to describe colors in a computer
这是描述计算机颜色的非常标准的方法
You have three different numbers telling you
用三个数来表述这个颜色
how much red, how much green,  how much blue is there
代表有多红，多绿，多蓝
if you're wondering what that X means
如果你想知道X代表什么
I would say don't worry about it too much right now
我觉得目前还不需要了解到那么细节
it's just a matter of padding
它只是一种填充
that can make internal data representations nice
可以让原始数据的表示更加美观
but if you wanted to play with this type
但是如果你探究这种变量类型
you could type something like RGBX and then type in a couple of potential values
你可以输入RGBX，然后输入随便几个值
for the red the green and the blue
分别代表红色，绿色和蓝色
which are going to be each between 0 and 1
它们都处在0和1之间
So if I type this
输入完以后
it actually gives me the color that those three values correspond to
它实际上给了我这个RGB值对应的颜色
And if maybe I increase the G part
如果我增加G部分
increase the green part
也就是绿色部分
I get an even greener image
我得到了更绿的颜色
but if I increase the red part
但是如果我增加红色部分
you know
没错
I would get an even redder image here to blend of red and green
我会在这里得到更红的图像，在这里红色和绿色混合
And if I turned down the others
如果我把另两种颜色值降低
you know
是的
we see something that's very much red
我们看到非常红的颜色
so that's the basic type
看得出是个很简单的类型
And this variable Philip that we have is an array of a whole bunch of those
我们前面的变量philip就是一系列的颜色变量
as you might expect, with an image
没错，一张图片就是一堆颜色
we could also ask about the size of Philip
我们也可以获取Philip的大小
they give us the dimensions
程序会给我们维度
So in this case, it's telling us 3675 * 2988
在这里，程序告诉我们大小是3675*2988
you might wonder which one of those is the height
也许你会好奇哪个数代表高度
which one of those is the width
哪一个是宽度
and we can basically just tell by taking a look at philip himself
我们看一下philip图片本身就知道了
and noticing that it's an image that's much taller than it is wide
注意到这是一张高度比宽度要大得多的图像
So that would suggest that this first variable was giving us the height
因此说明，第一个变量正在代表图像高度
And the second one is giving us the width
第二个代表图像宽度
which indeed it is
是真的
We can index directly into that array if we want to
我们也可以直接用下标来索引该数组中
So if I did Philip
所以如果我输入"philip[...]"
and then I want to go to
然后下标里面索引
the 100 pixel down from the top left
从上向下的第100个像素
and then the 400-th pixel in from the left
然后从左起第400个像素
it will return for us something that's an RGB type
它会为我们返回RGB类型的东西
So if I asked what's the type of this thing that it returned
所以如果我继续输出返回结果的类型
it's an RGB object
它是个RGB对象
but when the Pluto notebook to seize that
但是当Pluto笔记本获取输入时
it thinks that what we want to see is the color
它认为我们想要看的颜色本身而不是原始数值
which more often than not we probably do
很多情况下对我们来说很方便
so in this case
因此
it looks like I pulled out something that's black from that upper left
我们刚刚从图片的左上角获取了一个黑色的点
But maybe if I had gone down a lot farther
而如果我走得更再往下一点
you know, 1000 down
比如说... 往下1000个像素
and we're getting some blue parts
我们就得到了一个蓝色的点
so maybe that was coming somewhere from the rug
大概是地毯这边的的某个像素的颜色
we can also slice into this image where
我们也可以切割这张图片
let's say I wanted to go from the first pixel up to the 1000 pixel
假设我想获取竖直方向的第1个像素到第1000个像素
and then from the first pixel into the 400 pixel
水平方向的第1个像素到第400个像素
Something like that
诸如此类的东西
what this will return is another array
程序将返回另一个数组
it's an array that's basically a subset of the original picture
它是一个数组，代表了原始图片的一小块
So here it's just going from the upper left down by 1000 and in by 400
只是从左上角开始1000*400的一小块图片
which matches with what we see here
和我们在这里看到的相吻合
but that's maybe the least interesting part of the picture
但这也许是图片中最不有趣的部分
So maybe we want to do something like
也许我们更想
pull out the cute corgi himself
截取可爱的小柯基犬所在的那块图片
And so here I have a predefined block that does that for us
所以在这里有一个我之前写好的代码块，就可以做到这件事
Basically I take a look at the size
首先我们看一下原图尺寸
the height and the width
即高度和宽度
which I'm writing down as (h,w) equals the size of Philip
我写的是 (h,w)=size(philip)
and then we're going to pull out
然后我们要获取
just slice out a specific part of the array
数组切割后的结果
And here I'm going from halfway down the image
这里我截了图像的下半部分
all the way up to height itself
一直到图片底部
and here by the way
顺便说一句
we're using this division symbol
这里我们用了键盘上找不到的除号
So if in Julia
在Julia中
you type basically anything from Latex um and then you
你可以输入Latex语言中的几乎任何符号
with a backslash like `div'
只要用反斜杠开头，输入div，然后按Tab键
It lets us use more symbols than you usually can encode
这让我们可以用键盘上没有的符号来写程序
Because the spirit is that you want the code to read a lot like math
目的是让Julia写出来的代码像数学公式一样易读
So if I'm typing, you know like a nabla
因此，如果我输入反斜杠-nabla
this upside down triangle symbol
就会出现这个倒置的三角形符号
then I don't have to define that as a variable name
我们不必将其定义为一个变量
or various things like that
就能使用它
but in this case
不过现在
when we use that division symbol
当我们使用除法符号
what is doing is integer division
我们是在做整除
So it takes the height and divides by two
所以这里是在把高度除以二
but make sure to keep it of type integer
并且把结果取到一个接近的整数上
so it's taking that bottom half of the image
我们就因此获得了这张图片的下半部分
and then the width is going from 1/10 of the way into it
然后宽度上，我们从左起的1/10开始
until 9/10 of the way into it
一直到右边的9/10位置
and we're defining that as head
我们将这个结果定义为head
so now if I ask for
所以现在如果我们要查询
what's the size of head
head的大小是多少
we can see that it's something smaller
我们可以看到它比原图要小
And in fact
实际上
if we compare it to the size of Philip
如果我们将其与Philip的大小比较
we see that the first dimension is about half
我们看到第一维大约是原来一半
and then the next dimension is
然后第二个维度
that should be about 80%
应该是原来80％
which it is
的确是这样
so that's all well and good
目前一切顺利
This is how we can slice into arrays to pull out specific subsets
这就是我们对数组进行切片，来获得数组的一小部分的方法
Another nice thing we can do is concatenate arrays together
我们可以做的另一件事是将数组连接在一起
So if I type open bracket and then this head image that I had
因此，如果我输入左括号，head（这是我们之前获取的柯基图片）合
and then space
然后空格
and then another copy of that head image with the close bracket
然后再输入一次head，然后用右括号闭合
what we get is an array that just sort of smashes the two together
我们得到的是一个将两个head拼在一起的数组
so if I were to ask for the `typeof'
所以如果我用typeof()查询这个东西的类型
this subject
结果发现
it's the same type
它和刚才是同一类型
It's an array with these RGB values
是具有RGB值的数组
If I were to ask for its size
如果要知道它的大小
we see that it's actually much wider
我们会发现它比刚刚要宽得多
about twice as wide
大约两倍宽
which is what you would expect
这符合我们的预期
but again
不过无论如何
it displays it to us really nicely
这个拼起来的图看起来很棒
we could do some fun things with concatenation
我们可以通过拼接来做一些有趣的事情
like creating a kaleidoscopic corgi
比如创造一个“柯基万花筒”
So what we have here is basically four different concatenated images
我们这里有四个不同的图像拼接起来
We're in the upper left we have 'head'
我们在左上角是“head”
and in the upper right
在右上方
what I've done is
我做的是
reverse the head along the second dimension
把head沿第二维反转
So if I had just typed head in there
所以如果我像刚刚那样输入head
then that upper right image would be a copy of it
那右上方的图像就应该和原来一样
but if I reverse it
但如果我把它反转
`reverse(head)'
输入"reverse(head)"
then Julia is yelling at me that I haven't put in one of the keyword arguments to this function `reverse'
然后Julia提示说我没有对reverse传入参数
so I specify that the dimension along
因此我指定维度
which I want to reverse it is 2
在这里要沿第二根轴翻转
then it knows to basically flip that top image around
那么程序就会沿着垂直方向
around the vertical axis
翻转head这个图片
and you can read from here
然后你也可以看到
the lower left quadrant
左下象限
We've flipped it around the other axes
我们把它其沿另一个方向翻转
and in the bottom right
而在右下角
we've kind of flipped it around both
我们沿着两根轴一起翻转了
And that gets us this nice you know
因此，我们就得到了这张很棒的
multiple mirror image corgi thing
柯基的多重镜像图片
the point here though
不过，这里的重点是
is just how nice it is to concatenate arrays
拼接数组功能是多么的厉害
And we just have this open bracket & close bracket
并且我们用这个左括号，右括号
And then we write things down
然后像在数学公式那样
kind of as you would write it in a math context
把变量写在里面
just this matrix
就能够表达矩阵
with different elements in different spots
在不同的位置有不同的元素
Now, what we really want though
现在，我们真正想要的是
is to actually get into those pixels and start doing some interesting things with them
对每个像素进行深入操作，并开始做一些有趣的事情
and there's maybe two ways that we might think about this,
我们可能会尝试两种方式
one is to modify the array itself very directly
一种是直接修改数组本身
and the other one would be to copy the array to create a new object that's going to look different in some way
另一个将是复制数组，创建一个新对象，让它和原来的图片产生不同
so copying things as straightforward enough
Julia中复制东西很简单
we just call this function copy
我们只是调用函数“copy”
and when I've called this `new_phll' is equal to a copy of  `head'
当我声明new_phil，让它等于head的部分
That means we have a new variable, it's new data
我们就有一个新的变量，代表了新的数据
If we start manipulating this new_phil variable
如果我们开始操作此new_phil变量
it's not going to change the underlying data for `phil'
它不会更改phil中的原始数据
the thing that we originally pulled it out from
（phil是new_phil的来源）
so the goal right now is going to be to
所以现在我们要做的
basically just paint one of the corners of this
是把图片的某个角落
some monochromatic color like red
涂成单一颜色，比如红色
and there's two different ways that we could think about doing this
我们可以考虑两种不同的方法
one is to create a double for-loop where I'm going to take all the indices  i
一种是创建一个两层for循环，外层遍历所有i
ranging from 1 up to 100
范围从1到100
and then all the ones j, from 1 up to 100
然后内存遍历所有j，从1到100
or maybe I'll make that a different number like 300
诶，不妨改成一个不同的数字，例如300
So we'll be able to more easily see which index is affecting which dimension
这样我们就能更方便地看到哪个下标对应哪个维度
and then after that
然后在那之后
I will take my array new_phil
我将使用这个new_phil数组，
I will index into [i, j]
索引到[i，j]
And I'm going to ask it to become red
然后让这个像素变成红色
where red is a thing that I've previously defined above
其中红色是前面定义好的
an RGB value that is just (1, 0, 0)
RGB值是(1,0,0)的颜色
now you'll notice that
现在我们可以看到
unlike a lot of the other blocks
不像其他代码块
this one isn't showing us anything
这个代码块没有输出任何东西
'cause for loops themselves don't return anything
这是因为for循环本身不会返回任何东西
Since that I would have to act a retype
因此我需要重新输入
new_phil
new_phil
and we'll see that new_phil is indeed modified
我们将看到new_phil确实已被修改
and it looks like the j variable that was going from 1 to 300 is going along the horizontal direction
看起来j变量对应的是沿水平方向
and that kind of makes sense
这也很合逻辑
because the first thing that we do when we go to an array is go from top to bottom
因为我们操作数组时是先从上到下
And then the second thing is to start going inward
然后再是从左到右
you might think of it as being painted like one of those old style printers
其实这和那些老式的打印机的方法是一样的
that kind of goes left to right, left to right
就是那种左到右，左到右的方法
the way you would read a book
也就像你读书的方式
or any kind of pitch
或其他类似的东西
so that's nice
所以很好
We've modified our image
我们已经修改了我们的图片
but there's actually a much easier way if you want to just change all of
但是实际上，有一种更简单的方法
those pixels to be read without going through the for-loops to get into it
可以让我们不用写for循环就改变这些像素
and we can do what's known as broadcasting
我们可以做所谓的“广播(broadcasting)”
so here what I'll do is create yet another phil, new_phil2
所以在这里我要做的是创建另一个phil, 叫做new_phil2
That's copying new_phil itself
这是new_phil的一个副本
and then I'm going to slice into it when I'm going
然后我要对它切片时
from the 100 pixel up to the 200 pixel.
从上到下100像素到200像素
So that's going to be
所以这其实是
from the bottom of where we painted red down further
刚刚我涂红的地方的下面的位置
and then from the first up to the hundredth
然后从左到右是1到100的像素
which goes on only a third of the way in as the red rectangle did
是原来的涂红的矩形的三分之一大小
and then I'm going to say
然后输入
Dot equals RGB(0,1,0)
点等于(“.=”) RGB (0,1,0)
which is basically saying it's all green
这是在把这一小块的像素都变成绿色
and none of the other colors
其他颜色都没有
and what this dot is doing is saying
这里的点表示
Hey, this operation I'm asking you to do
你在告诉程序
rather than doing it to the object itself
不要对这个等号左边的这个对象（数组）本身进行操作
I want you to look into all the elements
而是要让程序对于数组中的每一个元素一个个进行操作
of this array and apply to each one of them individually
要是要让程序对于数组中的每一个元素一个个进行操作
So this is doing the same thing as the for-loops that we had above
因此，这和我们上面的for循环在做同样的事情
but syntactically it's a lot nicer to look at
但是语法上，它看起来要好得多
this little dot idea of broadcasting across arrays is actually quite common in Julia
实际上，在数组中用“点等于”进行广播的想法在Julia中非常普遍
and you can do it with functions
你还可以把广播和函数结合起来
It doesn't have to be assigning variables like this
而不必像这样，做单纯的变量赋值
And let me show you what I mean by that
来，让我们瞧瞧这是怎么做的
let's say I write some kind of function that I want to happen to each individual pixel
假设我写了一个函数，想把它作用在每个像素上
And in this case
在本例中
I'm defining a function called "redify"
我正在定义一个名为“redify”的函数
where "redify" is going to take in a variable
在“redify”传入一个变量
We go give it a better name
oh，换个变量名
or give it something like "color"
不如命名为“color”
so it's going to take in a color
我们传入一个颜色
and then what it returns is a new RGB value
然后这个函数会返回一个新的RGB值
where the red is pulled straight from colour "color.r"
这个新颜色只保留了旧颜色中的红色分量（“color.r”）
And then it has no green and has no blue
而丢弃掉了所有蓝色和绿色
So basically it says,  give me a pixel
所以本质上，这个函数是在把一个像素
I'm going to strip out its blue and green value
去掉它的蓝色和绿色值之后
just keep its red value and give it back to you
仅保留其红色值，然后返回
so as an example
所以，举个栗子
let's say I define some kind of color that has values (0.8, 0.5, 0.2)
假设我定义了一种RGB值为(0.8,0.5,0.2)的颜色
So it's this nice sort of brownish value
看起来是个很棒的褐色
or maybe we rob it of some of its red
也许我们减少一点红色的分量
and we get this sort of greenish value here
然后得到这个绿不拉几的颜色
if I were to display a list, that's `[color, redify(color)]`
如果我要显示一个列表 [[color, redify(color)]
what is showing us is the original color
程序会首先显示原始的颜色
And then what happens when we call redify to it
以及颜色在输入redify之后输出出来的颜色
so no matter what color goes in
无论输入什么颜色
it's pulling out just the red part
redify就只是在保留这个颜色中红色的部分
simple function
这是个很简单的函数
not something you would really use in practice
你不一定会在真正的应用当中用到
but the reason for defining it is to show you an example of what broadcasting can look like
但我们这里定义这个函数的原因，是为了展示广播的用法
because let's say we take the array that is Philip himself
比如说，我们redify广播后作用在把数组Phillip上
and we call "redify.(philip)"
只需要调用“ redify.(philip)”
what is doing is it's applying this function across all of Philip
这就是在把redify作用在整个Philip上
so if I didn't have that dot
所以如果我不写这个点
if I just tried to call "redify(philip)"
如果我只是调用“ redify(philip)”
it's giving me this error
程序会报错：
It's like "type Array has no field r"
“Array类型没有字段r”
and the reason that it's doing that is because when you call the redify function
报错的原因是当redify函数被调用时
it thinks that it's taking in a color
它认为参数color是一个颜色
And the thing that it does with that color is call `dot r'
然后试图获取参数color的分量r
as if it was going to be of the appropriate type
默认输入参数的类型是正确的
but it complains to us for that
但事实并非如此，因此程序报错了
of course
当然
if we broadcast it across all of the pixels of philip
如果我们在philip的所有像素之间广播
those are of the correct type
那就是正确的类型
So when I do that we see this very
调用之后可以看到 这张照片
it's kind of like when one of those old school film development rooms
就有点像是在老式的胶卷房里
and maybe there's this wet picture of the corgi just kind of hanging as it develops
晾绳上面悬挂着的一张在显影的柯基照片
but I would encourage you
看到这里，我建议你
if you're playing with things right now to try to finding your own function
你可以自己试着写一个
that might do something else to the color
把颜色做些变换的函数
and then broadcasting across whatever image you want
然后通过广播的方式作用在你喜欢的任何一张图像上
if you're working with a really big image that makes things kind of slow
注意，如果作用在很大的图片上，这个操作可能会有点慢
and you want to just see what it looks like sped up
因此，如果你只是想快速的试试看你程序写的对不对
one kind of nice tactic is to use this decimate function where
一种不错的策略是使用采样功能
if we call "decimate" on one of our arrays
如果我们对数组使用decimate函数
it basically pulls out
程序会把这个数组缩成一个更小的数组
In this case
在这
I think it's pulling out every fifth element
程序会把每5个元素保留一个
But I could ask it to pull out something like every 10th
不过我们也可以10个保留一个
and it's pulling out every tenth element
就像这样
Or if I said,  pull out every other element
或者，还可以每两个保留一个
so clearly decreases the quality
当然图片质量会下降
And as far as image compression goes
就图像压缩而言
it's not the most sophisticated scheme
这个方法不是很复杂，
but it's a nice way to just take what was a large image and then make it a smaller image that looks roughly the same
但是也不错，可以把原图缩成一张看起来差不多的小图片
But here, of course
但当然
it's of a poor quality
图像的分辨率就很低了
so if we asked for something like
所以如果我们想要知道
hey what's the size of poor_phil this new variable have defined
这个新变量定义的poor_phil的大小是多少
we see it's notably smaller
我们看到它明显较小
and so from here if we wanted a nice
所以，如果我们想要一个
small image to work quickly with
不错的小图片，以便快速使用
we could have "poor_phil"
我们可以叫它“poor_phil”
which is all well and good
不错哦
for example
例如
one of the interesting things that we're going to get into mostly in Lecture 2
我们可以做些很厉害的事情。虽然这主要是第二讲的内容
But I want to give you a little preview of things today
但是我们今天可以先管中窥豹
is this idea of a convolution
那就是卷积
This is very common in image processing
这在图像处理中很常见
It's basically a way that we can go through each pixel and
这是一种我们可以遍历每个像素
do something to it based on the neighbors of that pixel
并根据该像素周围的几个像素，来对其进行操作的方法
and again we'll go over all of the map of that next time
再次提醒，我们会在下一节课里详细讲这个内容
but just as an initial preview
不过不妨碍我们在这边先预览一下
I'm calling a function called convolve
我正在调用一个称为卷积的函数
I'm inputting "poor_phil"
输入参数“poor_phil”
the kind of decimated version of our puppy head
就是我们刚刚采样得到的小狗头
um and then I'm giving this other thing called "blur(2)"
然后第二个参数传入blur(2)
And if you were curious what "blur(2)" is
如果你想知道“blur(2)”是什么
you can just take a look at it
我们可以直接把它打印出来看看
and we can see that it's a two by two array of floats
可以看到，它是一个2x2的浮点数组
It's got certain values
有预先设置好的值
And based on what we talk about in the next lecture
如果听了我们在下一讲中讨论的内容
it'll maybe be clearer why this does what it's about to do
你也许会更清楚这个数组是干什么的
but if I call this convolve function with the array and that blur(2), it makes it a little bit blurrier
但是如果我调用这个卷积函数，传入这个数组和blur(2)，结果是让这个图片更加模糊一点
And that's a little bit clearer
但还是比较清楚地
if I have more of a blur, like blur(10)
如果我传一个模糊值更大的参数，比如说10
and if I were to look at the value of blur 10
可以用同样的方法查看blur(10)的值
we see it’s much bigger array
这是一个更大一点的数组
and got a bunch of other values in there
有另外一组预先设置好的值
and you might be able to guess at the moment that what this is doing is
你现在可能已经可以猜出这个东西是用来干嘛的了
taking a kind of average of all of the pixels around a particular pixel
它是在取特定像素周围所有像素的平均值
And by taking that average
通过取平均值
it kind of, makes the picture look out of focus to us
使图片看起来有虚焦的效果
So if there were only blur of one
所以如果只有blur(1)
we actually get the original image
结果实际上就是原始图像
But then as you increase that value a little bit more than it gets blurrier and blurrier
但是，当这个blur值增加时，图片会变得越来越模糊
and this thing that I'm doing right here
注意，让我们在调试观察时
where I'm trying to change this variable
如果需要修改这个变量的话
and I'm changing it one at a time
需要一次次的输入不同的值
At least while we're in the context of Pluto
不过在Pluto中
we can do this in a nicer way
其实我们有更好的办法来调试
with these notion of UI elements.
我们可以使用UI（User Interface, 用户界面）元素
so if we start using this library PlutoUI
我们可以导入PlutoUI这个库
then we can do things like creating a slider
然后，比如说，创建一个滑块
where I'm going to bind a variable called blur_factor to a slider
然后将一个名为blur_factor的变量绑定到滑块
And the slider is going to have values from 1 up to 20
滑块的值将介于1到20之间
I want to show what it's value is
同时在屏幕上实时显示这个值
right now it's showing us the one
像现在这个值就是1
But if I were to change it a little bit
而如果我操作一下
it shows us another value
它就会显示了另一个值
and now we can take that variable
现在我们可以使用该变量
I can have the same line that we had before
就用和之前演示中一样的代码
which was convolving poor_phil with blur
也就是对poor_phil用blur核进行卷积
according to some number that I'm putting into it
blur的参数是我输入的数字
But here I can do in a more interactive way
但现在就可以通过人机交互的方式进行
which is kind of nice, so again
很不错吧
if this is something that you're playing with
如果你正在探索某个程序的效果
this makes it a nice way to just tweak the variables to see the effect
那么用这种方法调整变量是个不错的主意
that it has on whatever function you're coming to be familiar with
它可以让你用来熟悉任何一个你想了解的函数的功能
so right now,
所以现在
food for thought for anyone watching this is
任何观看此影片的人都可以想一想
I want you to think about exactly what blur is probably doing
我建议你考虑一下blur是做什么用的
Like I said, you know
就像我说的
it's taking each part of the image and it's changing it based on the neighbors around it
它将处理图片的每一个像素，并根据周围的邻近的像素对其进行修改
And this whole idea
这个大概的意思
which we can kind of write in pseudo code here
可以像这样用伪代码表达：
where each element of an image you index into it at [i,j]
对于图像的每个元素（下标[i, j]）
you doing something based on the neighborhood
函数的结果是由其相邻的一些元素决定的
that is a thing being really powerful
这是个很强大的工具
and if that something is simply an average or more sophisticated kind of average
如果这个函数只是一个平均数或更复杂的平均数
you typically get a blurring effect
通常会产生模糊效果
But we can do smarter things with it
但是我们可以用它做更智能的事情
And one of the things you're going to do in the first problem set
您要在第一次作业中要做的一件事
is actually take that idea of just looking at a pixel
就是要试着通过某个像素的信息
and then looking at all of its neighbors
加上周围像素们的信息
and using that to try to pull out
来检测这个图像的边缘在哪里
so in this context
所以在这种情况下
if I call a function which you are going to define, called edge_detect
最终的效果就大概是，调用一个你自己写的函数，比如叫edge_detect
on "poor_phil"
作用在“poor_phil”上
it pulls out a lot of the little edges in there
它画出了很多小边缘
And then one thing that you might play around with his
然后我们可以再深入研究一下
what would happen if I smoothed out
要是我先做一次平滑（即模糊）操作
fill a little bit beforehand
之后再进行边缘检测
I might convolve poor_phil
我可以使用卷积，convolve(poor_phil)
with a blur maybe a blur_factor of 3
比如说是模糊因子3
and it's yelling at me because of some invalid syntax
oh程序出错了，报错显示是语法错误
uh premature input
emm （小哥debug中）
and then I'm plugging in the output of that edge detect
（仍然debug中）
...oh I just don't have enough parenthesis... great
...哦，我只是括号没补全...OK了
if I take a smoothed version
如果我用了一个平滑后的图片
it's finding fewer edges
程序将只会检测到更少的边缘
which kind of makes sense
这很合理
because the smoother it is
因为一个图片越平滑
the fewer edges there are to be found
找到的边缘就越少
but that's all something that we're going to dig into a little bit more in detail in the next lecture
不过这些都是我们在下一节课当中要仔细讲的事情了
before then
在那之前
I would encourage you to start thinking about how this might work
我希望你开始思考，这东西是怎么实现的呢？
How is it that you figure out what the edges are
什么是边缘？如何检测边缘？
especially if it's in a noisy environment
特别是，如果在很杂乱的画面中
what can we do to try to overcome that noise
我们该怎么做才能克服图片中的干扰?
and again
再次提示
edge detection is actually quite useful in a lot of scientific applications
边缘检测在许多科学应用中非常有用
You take a picture of a bunch of cells
比如，你拍了一堆细胞的照片
and you want to know how many cells there are in there
你想知道那里有多少个细胞
and you want to do that in kind of an automated way
但你不想自己数，想让计算机自动帮你数
A classic first step would be to detect the edges
那一个经典解法就是从检测边缘开始
to make it a simpler image
把原始照片转换为一个更简单的图片
as we move forward
随着课程的深入
we're going to start doing some more sophisticated things with these
我们将开始用这些做一些更复杂的事情
and it's going to get good
程序也会越来越酷炫
I think you're going to enjoy where we're going with this
你也会越来越享受这个过程